Matthew Bowen

North Baltimore, OH | 330-391-4059 | MB.Bowen@outlook.com gruzzly.co | github.com/Gruzzly-bear | linkedin.com/in/matthew-bowen-oh

Professional Summary

 Highly skilled software development professional bringing more than 8 years in software design, development and integration. Offering advanced knowledge of Front End development, Front End design and Back End programming languages.

Skills

Programming/Development: HTML/CSS, JavaScript, Python, C#, LUA

Frameworks/Libraries: .NET, Node.js, React, Bootstrap

Database:MySQL, SQL Server 2019IDEs:Visual Studio, Eclipse, IDLE

Project Management: Agile/Scrum, Azure **Version Control:** GitBash, GitHub

UI/UX Photoshop, Figma, Illustrator

Experience

Designer/Embroiderer | Innovative Stitching

Jul 2015 - Current

- Using a CAD-like program (Design Shop Pro), I designed files for customers, maintained computer environments and troubleshooted various issues.
- Fixed and maintained large mass production embroidery machines.
- Tech Support for the business software itself and multiple computers running windows.
- Converted art into stitches by vectorizing and digitizing the source into a compatible format for the machines.

Software Developer | Smarta

Jul 2020 - May 2021

Started out initially as a dart and flutter intern. It ended up switching almost immediately to Javascript and React. Using screens developed in various Adobe programs and Figma, I was able to use React/material UI to develop some fully functional pages. I also learned a lot about the React Native framework and how it can be used to develop mobile applications. I went from almost zero knowledge of React Native to using it to develop a mobile application within a few months.

Software Developer Intern | Prosper IT Consulting

Mar 2020 - Jul 2020

Internship consisted mostly of .net development with C#. It was a great hands-on experience. I was also given the freedom to play around with nosql databases like mongoDB and firebase, to try a few things out. I was fixing bugs and adding features, like a calendar. It was for a local theatre company in Oregon. It was a live coding project. I learned a lot about the .net stack and how it can be used to develop web applications.

Education and Training

Certification in Software Development | The Tech Academy

Intensive, boot camp-style training with more than 600 hours of instruction and hands-on work in:
Fundamentals of Computer Science, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, C#, Python, ASP.Net, web application
development, WordPress, object-oriented programming, Agile/Scrum, source control, relational
database design and management, SQL programming and more.